Lindquist, Jennie D.; Papers mss019
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Jennie D. Lindquist Papers1937-1978
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Lindquist, Jennie D. (Jennie Dorothea), 1899-1977
mss019
2 cubic ft.
The Jennie D. Lindquist papers document the professional life of Lindquist, an editor, author, lecturer, and librarian. The collection is cheifly composed of copies of personal correspondances, printed materials, transcripts from her radio program, and an advanced publisher's copy of her book.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by the Bryn Mawr Bookshop.
Biographical Sketch
Lindquist was a staff member of the Horn Book (the Boston publisher) from 1948 to 1958 and was editor of its Horn Book Magazine. She was also head of the Children's Department at the Albany Public Library, a lecturer and librarian at the University of New Hampshire, and an employee of The John Mistletoe Bookshop.
Scope and Contents
Chiefly personal correspondence with Helen T. Fay, Eleanor M. Foote, printed materials, transcripts of her 1940s New Hampshire radio program "Good Books for Boys and Girls," and a publisher's advanced copy of her book The Crystal Tree (New York: Harper and Row, 1966).
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Literature; Albany, New York; Albany Public Library (N.Y.); Children's librarians; Children's literature; Letters (correspondence); Manuscripts for publication; book jackets; Transcripts; Newsletters; Clippings (information artifacts); biographies (documents); Lindquist, Jennie D.; Horn Book, Inc.
- Manuscripts, 1944-1947, undated, 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically
  - Radio Broadcasts from U of Newhampshire 1944-1945, by Jennie D. Lindquist (Box 1 (1- Manuscripts, 1944-1947, undated), Folder 1)
  - "The Golden Name Day", dust jackets and end-paper, Undated (Box 1 (1- Manuscripts, 1944-1947, undated), Folder 2)
  - "The Little Silver House", dust jackets, Undated (Box 1 (1- Manuscripts, 1944-1947, undated), Folder 3)
  - "The Crystal Tree", [Advance, uncorrected proofs], dust jackets, Undated (Box 1 (1- Manuscripts, 1944-1947, undated), Folder 4)
  - Esther Averill, "Jenny and the Cat Club", typewritten manuscript with corrections, Undated (Box 1 (1- Manuscripts, 1944-1947, undated), Folder 5)
  - Carolyn Sherwyn Bailey,"Miss Hickory", handwritten manuscript, Chapters 3-13, 15. (Ch. 1-2, 14 missing), Undated (Box 1 (1- Manuscripts, 1944-1947, undated), Folder 6)
  - Erik Berry, Rough Sketch, circa 1947 (Box 1 (1- Manuscripts, 1944-1947, undated), Folder 7)
- Letters, 1938-1977, undated, 2
  Arranged Chronologically where possible
  - Undated letters to Dragon/Helen Fay from Wren/Jennie Lindquist(l) (Box 1 (2-Letters, 1938-1977, undated), Folder 1)
  - Undated letters to Dragon/Helen Fay from Wren/Jennie Lindquist (11) (Box 1 (2-Letters, 1938-1977, undated), Folder 2)
  - Undated "Cat Letters" (Box 1 (2-Letters, 1938-1977, undated), Folder 3)
  - Letters to Helen Fay mostly from J.L./Wren, 1938-1967 (Box 1 (2-Letters, 1938-1977, undated), Folder 4)
  - Letters to Helen Fay, mostly from Elizabeth Halbrooks, 1971-1977 (Box 1 (2-Letters, 1938-1977, undated), Folder 5)
  - Carolyn B. Hill (Carolyn Sherwyn Bailey) correspondence, 1954, 1957, 1950. (Box 1 (2-Letters, 1938-1977, undated), Folder 6)
  - Letters to Eleanor Foote, mostly from J.L./Wren, 1940-1959 (Box 1 (2-Letters, 1938-1977, undated), Folder 7)
  - Letters to Eleanor Foote, mostly form J.L./Wren, undated. (Box 1 (2-Letters, 1938-1977, undated), Folder 8)
  - Letters to Helen Fay and Eleanor Foote (together) from J.L., 1945, 1952, undated. (Box 1 (2-Letters, 1938-1977, undated), Folder 9)
  - Letters and notes to Jennie Lindquist, 1942-1943, 1945, 1948, 1956, 1950, 1967, 1975, and undated., 1942-1948; 1950-1956 (Box 1 (2-Letters, 1938-1977, undated), Folder 10)
- Vertical File, 1946-1978, undated, 3
  - Undated "biography" of J. Lindquist (Box 1 (3-Vertical File, 1946-1978, undated), Folder 1)
  - Booklists and New Hampshire Library Association's Newsletter, 1946, announcing J. Lindquist's resignation (Box 1 (3-Vertical File, 1946-1978, undated), Folder 2)
  - "The Horn Book Crier", a bimonthly newssheet issued by "The Horn Book, Inc." Not all issues: 1961, 1963, 1964, 1966, 1968, 1971-1978., 1963-1954 (Box 1 (3-Vertical File, 1946-1978, undated), Folder 3)
  - "The Horn Book", History and publications, Undated (Box 1 (3-Vertical File, 1946-1978, undated), Folder 4)
  - Horn Book Magazine proofs, Undated (Box 1 (3-Vertical File, 1946-1978, undated), Folder 5)
  - Horn Book page proof, Sept. 1951, "A Child in a Bookshop" by J. Lindquist (Box 1 (3-Vertical File, 1946-1978, undated), Folder 6)
  - Horn book replica, Undated (Box 1 (3-Vertical File, 1946-1978, undated), Folder 7)
  - "Horn Spectacles", monthly newssheet issued by Horn Book, not all issues from 1952-1955, 1957-1958 (Box 1 (3-Vertical File, 1946-1978, undated), Folder 8)
  - Newspaper clippings and misc., 1951, 1959, 1966, 1974, 1975, undated (Box 1 (3-Vertical File, 1946-1978, undated), Folder 9)
  - Mary K. O'Donnell's Seminar Paper on Jennie D. Lindquist, submitted May 1968 (Box 1 (3-Vertical File, 1946-1978, undated), Folder 10)